<u>CON</u>TACT ME AT

(514) 577 0827

meining.cheng@gmail.com

https://meiningcheng.com

in Meining Cheng

Meining2020

SKILLS SUMMARY

HTML5 CSS3 Sass

JavaScript (ES6+) jQuery React

Responsive Design Accessibility

Firebase RESTful APIs

Version Control Git & Git Hub

Group Programming Code Review

Java Python

Project Management

Problem Solving & Analysis

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

Juno College of Technology

Web Development Immersive Bootcamp | Apr - Jun 2021 JavaScript course | Feb - Apr 2021 Web Development course | Nov - Dec 2020

McGill University

Master of Science, Food Science | Jan 2017 - Oct 2018

University of Manitoba

Bachelor of Science, Food Science | Jan 2015 - Feb 2017 (Graduated with Distinction)

MEINING CHENG

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am an enthusiastic front-end developer with a passion for building engaging, accessible, and responsive websites and apps. My experience working as a Quality Assurance manager in facedpaced manufacturing industries cultivated my abilities to make sound and meticulous decisions as well as handle complex tasks synchronously.

PROJECTS

Foodie's Cookbook (view live | repo)

React | Firebase | API | JavaScript | HTML | CSS

 A react based app that allows users to enter a keyword to search food recipes, filter results, and save recipes

Backronym Generator (view <u>live | repo</u>)

React | Firebase | API | JavaScript | HTML | CSS

 A client-based application that generates a backronym which is an acronym created from an existing word. This is a group project built collaboratively with teammates.

TMDB Movie Fun (view live | repo)

JavaScript | API | Pair Programming | HTML | Sass

 A movie app that allows users to search movies by titles and genres and obtain detailed information about the movie and cast.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Quality Compliance Manager

NutraLab Canada Corp. | Nov 2020 - Mar 2021

- Supervised a team of 6 Quality Technicians and trained 75 plant employees on Good Manufacturing Practices
- Liaised between customers, sales, engineering, and manufacturing to resolve customer complaints
- Directed about 100 quality-compliant products release per month
- Led 3rd party certification and audit programs

QA/QC Associate

NutraLab Canada Corp. | Jan 2019 - Nov 2020

- Performed in-process inspection to ensure manufacturing instructions and product specifications are followed
- Analyzed product safety and quality data to prepare daily reports for leadership
- Maintained and updated quality documentations